[{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap:&nbsp;University students _________ behave well.&nbsp;&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Can","Should","May","Must"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap: Gloria&nbsp;____________ have finished the project two days ago.&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Must","May","Can","Supposed to"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap: Gloria&nbsp;____________ have finished the project two days ago.&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Must","May","Can","Supposed to"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap: You are Goodluck, _________?&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Are you?","Aren\u0092t you?","Are\u0092nt you?","Don\u0092t you?"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap: He _________ not come now&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Needs","Needed","Need","Will need"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap: Janet________ to know that we are all here<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Suppose","Supposes","Is supposed","Should suppose"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap: Let it be _________ that there was no king in Ayegun.&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Know","Knew","Known","Knows"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap: We shall see you soon, ?&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Shall we ?","Shan\u0092t we?","Shouldn\u0092t we","Should we"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap: Neither of the presidential candidates _________ suitable.&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Are","Is","Is been","Are been suitable."],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap: Ten miles ____ a great distance.&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["is","Are","Is been","Was been"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap: If I were the president, I _______ ask for the money&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Will","Should","Would","Can"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap: I will see you after I ________ spoken with your supervisor.&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Might have","Have","Will have","Would have"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap: &ldquo;You .....- now see the director&rdquo;, the secretary told the visitors&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Can","May","Should","Would"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap:&nbsp;She isn&rsquo;t Gloria ________ ?&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Is she ?","Isn\u0092t she ?","Aren\u0092t she ?","Doesn\u0092t she ?"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap: We have a bus, _______?&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Didn\u0092t we ?","Haven\u0092t we ?","Doesn\u0092t we ?","Hasn\u0092t we ?"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap: I knew David ______ let us down.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["May","Will","Might","Can"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap: You ________ me last week.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Ought to see","Ought to had seen","Ought to have seen","Had to have seen"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap: Twenty dollars ___ enough for my lunch.&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Are","Is","Are just","Was just"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap: The pests ____ our farm every year.&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Invade","Invades","Has invades","Had invades"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap: If I were the Governor, I _______ ask for the project&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Will","Should","Would","Can"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap: When ______ the Cleric ______ today?&nbsp;&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Does\/arrives","Does\/arrived","Does\/arrive","Do arrive"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap: We shall see you soon, _________?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Shall we?","Shan\u0092t we?","Shouldn\u0092t we","Should we"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap: You missed the match, _______?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Don\u0092t you?","Didn\u0092t you?","Hadn\u0092t you?","Doesn\u0092t you?"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap: Walk the dog right now, _______?&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Walkn\u0092t you?","Will you?","Shall you?","Would you?"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap: I am a student, _______?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["I\u0092m I?","Aren\u0092t I?","Isn\u0092t I?","Wouldn\u0092t I?"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Pick out the odd\/wrong expression in each of the following :<\/strong><\/p>","options":["I heard his supposed apology","I heard his unconvincing apology","I heard his suppose apology","I heard he was supposed apology"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Pick out the odd\/wrong expression in each of the following :<\/strong><\/p>","options":["I suppose you know the way","I am supposed you know the way","I suppose he knows the way","They suppose he knows the way"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Pick out the odd\/wrong expression in each of the following :<\/strong><\/p>","options":["I travel next week","I will travel next week","I suppose to travel next week","I should travel next week"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Pick out the odd\/wrong expression in each of the following :<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Having discovered the error, he apologized","Having discovered the error, the apology was tendered","Having known the error, he apologised","Having found out the error, he tendered an apology"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Pick out the odd\/wrong expression in each of the following :<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The job has been done","The job has been being done","They have done the job","They can have done the job"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Pick out the odd\/wrong expression in each of the following :<\/strong><\/p>","options":["She must finish the project in two days","She must finish the project two days ago","She must have finished the project two days ago","She ought to have finished the project two days ago"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Pick out the odd\/wrong expression in each of the following :<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["If I went in there, I would beat the security officer","If I go in there, I would beat the security officer","If I go in there, I will beat the security officer","If I go in there, I can beat the security officer"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that most appropriately expresses the idea in the&nbsp;<\/strong><strong>underlined expression.<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>My friend&rsquo;s parent&rsquo;s are <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">magnanimous <\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Rich and popular","Sociable and lovable","Kind and generous","Wicked and stingy"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that most appropriately expresses the idea in the underlined expression.&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>My friend has an <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">overbearing<\/span> attitude toward me&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Patient","Impatient","Opinionated and domineering","Considerate and respectful"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>There are a number of <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">makeshift building&nbsp;<\/span>&nbsp;in town&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Modern buildings","Old fashion buildings","Temporary buildings","Permanent buildings"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that most appropriately expresses the idea in the underlined expression.<br \/>Post UME is a <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">hurdle to cross.&nbsp;<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["A necessary and simple exam to pass","An unnecessary and difficult exam to pass","An unnecessary but simple exam to pass","A necessary and challenging exam to pass"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p style=\"text-align: left;\"><strong>Choose the option that most appropriately expresses the idea in the underlined expression.<\/strong><\/p>\n<p style=\"text-align: left;\"><strong>His contribution to the project is <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">invaluable<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Extremely useful","Of no value","Of little value","Can not be valued"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that most appropriately expresses the idea in the underlined expression.<br \/>That was a <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">dawn-to-earth<\/span> approach&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Poor","Ordinary","Practical","Immodest"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that most appropriately expresses the idea in the underlined expression.<br \/>Concerning my admission, I have to <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">cross my fingers<\/span> <\/strong><\/p>\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["Wait and hope for the best","Wait in frustration","Wait confidently","Take some risk"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that most appropriately expresses the idea in the underlined expression.<br \/>My father is <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">indifferent<\/span> to my choice of University <\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["Supports","Opposes","Not decided","Not concerned"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that most appropriately expresses the idea in the underlined expression.<br \/>We need an <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">ad hoc<\/span> arrangement towards the project&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Intelligent","Advanced","Permanent","Temporary"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that most appropriately expresses the idea in the underlined expression.<br \/>The student&rsquo;s reply to the lecturer <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">betrayed<\/span> his rudeness <\/strong><\/p>\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["Covered","Showed","Reduced","Increased"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that most appropriately expresses the idea in the underlined expression.<br \/>His conduct in the last elections was <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">above board&nbsp;<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Arrogant","Honest","Above average","Excellent"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that most appropriately expresses the idea in the underlined expression.<br \/>That was a <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">dispassionate<\/span> decision&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Bias","Personal","Unaffected","Ineffective"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that most appropriately expresses the idea in the underlined expression.<br \/>On the matter of worship, some <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">sit on the fence<\/span> <\/strong><\/p>\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["Go to the extreme","Are decisive","Are fanatics","Are undecided"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that is nearest in meaning to the word underlined:&nbsp;In this matter, we must be prepared to tolerate human <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">frailty<\/span>.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Inquisitiveness","Weakness","Profligacy","Innovation"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that is nearest in meaning to the word underlined: I detest his <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">lackadaisical<\/span> attitude.&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Carefree","Lazy","Supercilious","Disloyal."],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that is nearest in meaning to the word underlined: Nobody will endure such <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">profligate<\/span> spending habits.&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Generous","Arrogant","Wasteful","Mindless."],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that is nearest in meaning to the word underlined: Is he <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">oblivious<\/span> of the political situation in his community?&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Unconscious","Conscious","Afraid","Intolerant."],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that is nearest in meaning to the word underlined:&nbsp; <\/strong><strong>Many people look into the future <\/strong><strong>with <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">trepidation<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Certainty","Uncertainty","Fear","Faith."],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that is nearest in meaning to the word underlined: Can you marry such a <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">lanky man?&nbsp;<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Tall and thin","Sturdy","Fat and short","Tall and short."],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that is nearest in meaning to the word underlined: The election system we adopted was his <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">brainchild.&nbsp;<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Undoing factor","Invention","Power","Fabrication"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option opposite in meaning to the word underlined.&nbsp;<\/strong><strong>Peter always approaches issues optimistically.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Realistically","Pessimistically","Carelessly","Unrealistically."],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Why should Dixon be evasive in answering the question?&nbsp;<\/strong><strong>Choose the option opposite in meaning to the word underlined.<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["Indirect","Direct","Guessing","Sure."],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option opposite in meaning to the word underlined.&nbsp;&nbsp;John and Ahmed&rsquo;s ideas were <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">speculative&nbsp;&nbsp;<\/span><\/strong><\/p>\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["Stipulative","Superlative","Factual","Attractive."],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option opposite in meaning to the word underlined.&nbsp;Henry was admitted to the hospital with <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">profuse<\/span> bleeding<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["Much","Little","Internal","Continuous"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option opposite in meaning to the word underlined.&nbsp;Many people regard him as prolific<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["Diplomatic","Productive","Unproductivev","Unacademic."],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option opposite in meaning to the word underlined.&nbsp;Our success is <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">paramount<\/span> in his mind.&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["Unimportant","Important","Certain","Uncertain."],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option opposite in meaning to the word underlined.&nbsp;In all, I consider the behaviour <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">unpalatable.&nbsp;<\/span><\/strong><\/p>\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["Unacceptable","Offensive","Acceptable","Inoffensive."],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option opposite in meaning to the word underlined.&nbsp;Her action will certainly <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">exacerbate<\/span> the situation.&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["Ameliorate","Worsen","Aggravate","Clarify."],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option opposite in meaning to the word underlined.&nbsp;Is he really behaving <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">oddly<\/span> ?&nbsp;&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["Abnormally","Normally","Evenly","Properly."],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option opposite in meaning to the word underlined.&nbsp;<\/strong><strong>He always approaches issues optimistically.&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Realistically","Pessimistically","Carelessly","Unrealistically."],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option opposite in meaning to the word underlined.&nbsp;<\/strong><strong>Her health <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">deteriorated<\/span> rapidly. <\/strong><\/p>","options":["Worsened","Improved","Stagnated","Declined"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following sentences is correct?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["One should mind his business.","One should mind one\u0092s business","One should mind her business.","One should face his business"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following sentences is correct?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The dog wagged its tail"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following sentences is correct?<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["A ten year old boy is missing","A ten-year old boy is missing","A ten year-old boy is missing","A ten-year-old boy is missing"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the optiono that sounds the with <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\"><em>bear:<\/em><\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Bare","Beer","Bared","Beard"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the opiton that sounds the same with the given word. Key<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Kiss","Quay","Keyed","Kissed"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choos the opption that sounds the same with: <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\"><em>two<\/em><\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Tool","Too","Tow","To"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the word that is correctly spelled.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Acomodation","Accommodation","Accomodation","Acommodation"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the word that is correctly spelled.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Embarrassment","Embarassment","Embarrasment","Embarasment"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the word that is correctly spelled.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Embarrassment","Embarassment","Embarrasment","Embarasment"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the word that is correctly spelled.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Horrific","Horific","Horiffic","Horriffic"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>As soon as Joy arrived, she started looking for food. The underlined<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>expression is an ___________.&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Adverbial phrase of reason","Adverbial clause of reason","Adverbial phrase of time","Adverbial clause of time"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>My friend, a brilliant lecturer, won many prizes. The underlined expression is&nbsp;<\/strong><strong>a(n) _________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Adjectival clause","Relative  clause","Appositive phrase"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>I passed very well<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\"> because<\/span> I studied hard. The underlined expression is a(n) ___________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Relative clause introducer","Linking verb","Adverb of reason","Subordinating conjunction"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Bello and I love <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">each other<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Preposition","Reciprocal pronoun","Noun phrase","Adjectival phrase"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>I prefer writing to acting. The underlined expressions is a(n) __________.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Verb","Participle","Gerund","Object"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Having finished my assignment, I started watching television. The underlined&nbsp;<\/strong><strong>expression is a(n) _________.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Infinitive clause","Gerund","Participial phrase","Noun clause"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>If you leave early, you&rsquo;ll meet Sola at home. The underlined expression is a __________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Nominal clause","Verbal clause","Conditional clause","Adjectival clause"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Wounded by a lion, the hunter trudged home. The underlined expression is a _________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Nominal clause","Verbal clause","Participial clause","Adjectival clause"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>I&rsquo;m proud of you. The underlined expression functions as<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Prepositional complement","Adjectival complement","Subject complement","Verbal complement"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>A noun phrase lacks one of the following:&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Noun","Verb","Adjective","Adverb"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Eve gave Adam an apple. <em>An apple<\/em> in the sentence functions as__________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Subject of the verb \u0091gave\u0092","Direct object of the verb","Indirect object of the verb","Object complement"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>I wonder if you know where he lives. This sentence is a(n) _________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Thoughtful statement","Polite command","Polite command","Subtle exclamation."],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>An example of gradable adjectives is _______<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Each","Beautiful","Dead","Live"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>A clause differs from a phrase because a clause contains __________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["A larger number of words","A fewer number of words","A finite verb","A non- finite verb"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>An autobiographical novel is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["A novel written about another novelist","A true account of a novelist&#39s life by himself","A novel in which the novelist draws mainly on materials from his own life","A novel using the &#39I&#39 pronoun"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Plot in prose fiction is best defined as<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The cause and \u0097 effect sequence of events","The brief summary of events",".The central event","The subject \u0097 matter of a novel"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of these is not true about unity of action in a novel?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Action may be unified through a single main character","Action may be unified by being set in one place","Action may be unified by many characters",".Action may be unified by having one consistent point of view"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Action in a novel is best defined as:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The summary of the novel\u0092s story","What the characters do or say in the novel","The numerous sub \u0097 plots of the novel put together",".The totality of all the episodes in a novel leading to the conclusion"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Suspense in a novel means<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The postponement of the hero<span>'<\/span>s death till the last possible moment","The intense emotions that the author conveys","The inconclusive end of a novel","When we are curious about what happens next in a"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>A realistic novel is one in which the characters are<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Real","Historic","Just of above average intelligence","The types that we meet in everyday life"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Theme is best defined as<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The subject matter of a novel or play","Central idea in a play or novel","The point of view in that novel",".The sum \u0097 total of all the characters experiences"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>What figure of speech does the following quotation<\/strong><br \/><strong>contain? Life&rsquo;s but a walking shadow (Macbeth)<\/strong><\/p>","options":["A metaphor","An image","A synecdoche","An allusion"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following statement is most true about<\/strong><br \/><strong>poetry?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The meaning of words are more important than their sounds","The sounds of words are more important than their meanings","The sound of words are often more important than their meanings","Sounds and meanings of words are of little consequence"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of these best define exposition in drama?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The author<span>&#39;<\/span>s own general introduction to the play","The author<span>&#39;<\/span>s early exposure of his dramatist personae to conflict","Introduction to the characters and the general problem with which the play deals","The first performance of the play on stage"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>When the speaker in a poem cannot be identified with<\/strong><br \/><strong>the poet, that speaker is called<\/strong><\/p>","options":["A persona","A dramatist persona","A soliloquist","Aventriloquist"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of these definitions best describes a lyric?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["A short poem","A short poem in which the poet himself is speaking","A poem expressing a personal idea, feeling or mood","A poem divided into stanzas"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Among rocks, I am the loose one, among arrows, I am<\/strong><br \/><strong>the heart among daughters, I am the recluse, among<\/strong><br \/><strong>sons, the one who dies young <\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>What kind of repetition is used in the extract?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Anaphora","Single word repetition","Line repetition","Phrase repetition"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Apart from emphasis, what other effect does the<\/strong><br \/><strong>repetition have?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Makes the poem rhythmical","Makes the poem tedious","Makes the poem monotonous","Makes the poem exhilarating"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>The following line from poem Western wind, when will<\/strong><br \/><strong>thou blow? Is an example of<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Rhetorical question","Caesura","Alliteration","Nature imagery"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Identify the odd one out of these types of imagery<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Visual imagery","Tactile imagery","Synaesthesia","Literal imagery"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>When a poet uses mainly soft vowel sounds in a<\/strong><br \/><strong>poem, the texture of the poem is:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Mellifluous","Harsh","Assonantal","Neutral"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>The sounds in the following lines may be described as<\/strong><br \/><strong>an example of: The moan of doves in immemorial elms,<\/strong><br \/><strong>and murmuring of innumerable bees<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Alliteration","Euphony","Cacophony","A mixture of all above"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>The man dies in him who keeps silent in the face of<\/strong><br \/><strong>tyranny&rdquo;. This statement can be described as<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Metaphoric","Literal","Tragic","A simile"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>The literary technique in which a reader is taken to<\/strong><br \/><strong>the past of a current action is known as:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Rewinding","Fast forward","Flashback","Repetition"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"}]